M.Saad Siddiqui

Phone +60102440732

Email to.msaads@gmail.com

m.saads Skype **Github** mazemax KL, Malaysia Location

Summary

Full stack developer with 8 years of professional experience. Used JavaScript, ReactJS, ExpressJS, GraphQL, NodeJS, HTML5, PHP and cloud stacks to provide enterprise level scalable software solutions.

Core Competencies

- **JavaScript**
- Webpack
- ElasticSearch
- ***** Sencha
- Symfony
- PostgreSQL
- **Jenkins**

- NodeJS
- Jest
- Mongodb
- MySOL
- Angular OpenUI5
- Buildkite

- ReactJS
- KoaJS
- SASS
- Android Laravel
- Docker
- GraphOL

- **TypeScript**
- **ExpressJS**
- Socket.io
- Twitter Bootstrap
- Apache Cordova
- Git
- NextJS

Achievements and Affiliations

- Migrated ThinkOfLiving React app to React Hooks [2019 2020] Improved web app performance
- Migrated Squarefoot project from NextJS V6 to V8 [2019] Improved web app performance
- * Rearchitected Huddle product for scalability [2018] - To serve 1000+ users
- Organized knowledge sharing DevMamak sessions [2017 2019] For MBDT employees
- * Reduced Geekunit web hosting costs up to 5x-10x [2015] - with introduction to Digital Ocean cloud hosting.
- Increased Geekunit developer's productivity up to 5x-10x [2015] with introduction to Gitlab and Docker.
- * Successful Implementation of 2Checkout mobile solution [2015] - Android and iOS platforms.
- SAP Business Suite powered by SAP HANA course [2014] Scored 96.1%. *
- Intro to SAP HANA by Dr. Vishal Sikka course [2014] Scored 100% and belongs to top 5% of participants
- ***** Intro to Mobile Solution Development for Enterprise course [2013] - Scored 95.8%
- ***** Certified Microsoft Tech Associate - Software Development Fundamentals [2011] - Scored 88/100
- 1st Position Procom Software Competition and Exhibition [2011] PHPKetchup Team-lead
- 2nd Position ACM Developers Day Software Competition [2011] PHPKetchup Team-lead

Professional Experience



Senior Developer, iProperty – REA Group Asia [2019 - Present]

Full stack development of web apps using JetBrains IDE. Tools and technologies used: NodeJS, JavaScript, NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, Webpack, PHP, Wordpress, MYSQL, Laravel Zero, Elastic Search, AWS, Buildkite, Docker etc.

- <u>Lifestyle</u> custom CMS product NextJS, GraphQL, MYSQL, Wordpress, AWS etc.
 - Full stack web development of Squarefoot and ThinkOfLiving projects. New features are being developed on bi-weekly basis.



Software Analyst, IPG Mediabrands [2017 - 2019]

Full stack development of web apps using JetBrains IDE. Tools and technologies used: NodeJS, JavaScript, KoaJS, ReactJS, Redux-Saga, Webpack, PHP, Symfony, PostgreSQL, Eloquent, Elastic Search, AWS, Jenkins, Docker etc.

- Huddle content portal ReactJS, KoaJS, Symfony, Postgres, Elastic Search, AWS etc.
 - Rewritten 95% of code-base to serve 1000+ users. Contains many micro-services over AWS.



Senior Software Engineer, Litmus Labs [2016]

Full stack development of web apps using JetBrains IDE.

- Momyaz Travel Travel and tours web application LAMP Stack, Yii
 - Full stack web development. Integrated TBOHolidays, Hotelbeds and Travelport APIs.



- Full stack web development. *Magento2* theme customization.



Chief Information Officer, GeekUnit [2014 - 2016]

Performed all DevOps related tasks. Published all mobile apps on app store. Trained and mentored all developers. Self learnt and implemented on-page SEO, financial and HR aspects.

- **❖** TAKSI Book Taxis and Mini cabs online MEAN Stack, Digital Ocean
 - Development, deployment and product management
- Africao Portal for tenders LAMP Stack, Yii, Sphinx, Digital Ocean
 - Development, deployment and product management
 - Supervised development of iOS and Android apps
- Asma3na5ir Radio website and mobile app for Tunisia LAMP Stack, Codeigniter
 - Development, deployment and product management
 - Supervised development of *iOS* and *Android* apps



Manager Software Engineer, Logic-Unit [2013 - 2014]

Manage social media accounts and guide junior resources in addition to development work. Tools and technologies used: HTML5, Sencha, Phonegap, Cordova, jQuery mobile, Android, Brackets, Eclipse, Visual Studio, VS Source Control, Node.js, JavaScript, CSS, PHP, Codeigniter, Apache, LAMP, MySQL, Filezilla, Evolus Pencil, NinjaMock, Ubuntu etc.

- ♦ StalkHawk Application to keep an eye on Facebook friends Sencha
 - Development and product management of Facebook apps
- **♦** American Tax An offshore website with Google store locator LAMP Stack
 - Development and deployment of website with Google store locator and admin section
- **★** Instalacions 77 An offshore installation administration mobile app
 - Developed mobile app using Phonegap for Android platform



Management Trainee, Otsuka Pakistan Ltd. [2012 – 2013]

Tools and technologies used are: SAP B1 2007, SAP Crystal Reports 2008, SAP B1DE, SAP Screen Painter, MS Visual Studio, C#, MS SQL, Win Server 2003, VNC software and Spiceworks etc

- **ERP Implementation** SAP Business One solution implementation at Otsuka
 - Performed testing and QA feedback tasks for requisition module implementation
 - Developed crystal reports and requisition utility in C#, SAP B I D E framework
- Spiceworks Helpdesk Helpdesk deployment during Quality Circle activities
 - Participated during meetings, installation, configuration, testing and presentation



Software Engineer, Creative Chaos Pvt. Ltd. [2011 – 2012]

Tools and technologies used: PHP, CakePHP, Yii, Zend, Sphinx, SVN, jQuery Mobile, jQuery, Croogo, BeanstalkApp, LighthouseApp, Filezilla, SQLyog, MySQL, JavaScript, JSON, AJAX, HTML5, Apache, LAMP, Ubuntu, GIMP, Wordpress, Netbeans etc.

- Jill's List An offshore web based health tech portal LAMP Stack, Croogo
 - Development of Referral Network, Dashboards, Google Calendar integration etc.
 - Maintenance and optimization of legacy code
- **❖** <u>Jubilee Life Insurance</u> A website developed for local customer Wordpress
 - Developed and integrated Plan Finder calculator Wordpress widget

Educational Background



SharePoint 2010 Administration [2012] CTTC Pvt. Ltd, Karachi



BS - Computer Science [2011]

Equivalent to MCS / M.Sc. Computer Science, 16 years' education, FAST NUCES, Karachi

Academic Research and Projects

- PHPKetchup PHP desktop app Framework [Final Year Project]
- Newsigniter News Aggregator [Codeigniter]
- Inventory Management System [Joomla] for Provincial Disaster Management Authority
- Virtual Screensaver WinASM
- Library Management System PASCAL
- Student Management System PASCAL

